Hey there, future physicists! Today we're
diving into Scalars and Vectors.
Scalar having magnitude But not have Direction
like east west south and north
vector having magnitude and also specified Direction
some of scalar quantity example are:
Thermometer
speedometer
Weight scale
Introduction to vector
Vectors, on the other hand, are a bit
more demanding.They have both magnitude and direction.
some of example of vector are:
wind flows in specified direction
Arrow moving toward target
the line represent the numerical value called magnitude
arrow represent the direction
Scalar addition is a algerabic addition
Addition of vector A and B is:
In vector addition, the resultant vector is equal to the
tail of first vector to the tip of second vector.
line represent resultant magnititude and arrow represent direction
On multiple the above vector with scalar 2 unit
vector magnitude increase by 2 times
similarly, vector magnitude decrease by multiplying them
with scalars between 0 to 1
Its direction change in opposite direction
on multiply by negative scalar
Same magnitude but different directions
means they're different vectors.
This blue vector represent you are moving
in a east direction with some magnitude
yellow vector represent you are moving in
a north direction with same magnitude